naa.gov.au 2017-12-17

# Privacy – National Archives of Australia, Australian Government

The National Archives of Australia (the Archives) is committed to protecting your privacy in accordance with the _Privacy Act 1988_ (Cth) (Privacy Act) including the _Australian Privacy Principles_ (APPs). The 13 APPs are a minimum set of standards, rights and obligations for how we handle and maintain people’s personal information. This includes the regulation of how we collect, store, use, disclose, quality assure and secure personal information, as well as your rights to access or correct your personal information.

### Your rights

The Privacy Act provides you with rights, including:

  * being told generally what kind of information we are collecting and how we collect it;
  * being told the purpose for which your personal information is being collected;
  * your personal information can only be collected for a lawful purpose;
  * being given the opportunity to deal with us anonymously or using a pseudonym where it is not impracticable to do so;
  * finding out what information we hold about you and have it corrected if you can show that it is incorrect, out of date or incomplete;
  * providing that your personal information must be stored securely and protected from interference or misuse; and
  * finding out how your personal information will be used.

You can also make a complaint to us about the way your personal information has been handled under the Privacy Act and we are required to consider and respond to your complaint.

### When the APPs apply

The APPs generally apply to records created or received by the Archives to carry out its functions and activities.

### When the APPs apply to older records

If an individual believes that their personal information contained on a Commonwealth record that is in the open access period is inaccurate, out-of-date, incomplete, irrelevant or misleading that individual may apply to the Archives to have the information amended. This request must be made under the _Freedom of Information Act 1982_ (FOI Act) rather than the Privacy Act but it reinforces your right under APP 13 to have your personal information corrected. Special considerations also apply to records in the Archives collection as these can only be destroyed or altered in accordance with the _Archives Act 1983_ (Cth) (Archives Act).

### The APPs do not apply to the Archives collection

The APPs do not generally apply to Commonwealth records in the Archives' collection.

The Archives is responsible for the custody and care of records in the 'open access' period. These are records created more than 26 years ago which form part of the Archives collection. The Archives collection is made up of approximately 40 million items (which includes records, images, maps, volumes and other objects) in over 80,000 series. They are the records of almost 10,000 past and present Commonwealth agencies and persons. The APPs have very limited application to the Archives collection.

The Archives collection is administered under the Archives Act. The Archives is required to make all records in the open access period available to the public unless they are exempt. When deciding if a record should be made available to the public your personal affairs will be considered in line with the Archives Access Examination Policy – personal, business and professional affairs of a person, rather than the APPs.

## Privacy Policy

The Archives Privacy Policy explains how the agency deals with personal information generally, including its collection, storage, security, access, use and disclosure. Further information about the agency’s handling of personal information is contained in the Archives Privacy Policy.

## If you have privacy concerns

If you are concerned about how we have collected or managed your personal information, you can read our Privacy Policy to familiarise yourself with our approach to privacy. You can also call the Archives' Privacy Contact Officer at the following contact points:

Telephone + 61 2 6212 3600 (callers within Australia)   
Speak and Listen users phone 1300 555 727 then ask for 02 6212 3900   
Internet Relay users connect to the National Relay Service then enter 02 6212 3900   
Fax +61 2 6212 3649   
Email [privacy@naa.gov.au](mailto:privacy@naa.gov.au)

Privacy Contact Officer   
National Archives of Australia   
PO Box 7425   
Canberra Business Centre ACT 2610   
Australia

If you are not satisfied with how we have handled your privacy concerns you can also contact the [Office of the Australian Information Commissioner](http://www.oaic.gov.au/ "Link opens in a new window") (OAIC) directly. The OAIC is independent to us and has the power to investigate complaints about possible interferences with your privacy. It is usually best to contact us first. While it is possible for the first contact to be with the OAIC, they will generally ask us to conduct our own enquiry first and pass any findings on to the OAIC.

## Visiting this website

The Archives makes a record of your visit to this site and logs the following information for statistical purposes:

  * your server address
  * your top-level domain name (e.g. .gov, .com, .edu, .org, .au, .nz etc)
  * which pages you accessed and which documents you downloaded
  * the date and time of your visit
  * the site from whence you came
  * your operating system (e.g. Windows, Mac)
  * which browser you used (e.g. Internet Explorer)

We will make no attempt to identify you or your browsing activities except, in the unlikely event of an investigation, where a law enforcement agency may exercise its authority to inspect the service provider's logs.

## Emailing us

The Archives will only record your email address if you send us a message. The address will be used only for the purpose for which you provided it. We will not use your email address for any other purpose and will not disclose it without your consent.

All correspondence and comments supplied to the Archives will be stored for a period of time as set down in the Administrative Functions Disposal Authority (AFDA).

## Using our online shop

The [Archives online shop](http://eshop.naa.gov.au/ "Link opens in a new window") provides a secure connection to your browser, meaning that you can be sure that your personal details and credit card number are safe when shopping online with us.

You can find out more about [safe shopping online](http://eshop.naa.gov.au/g/34716/online-security.html "Link opens in a new window") with the Archives.

## Our P3P statement

The Archives supplies information about its online privacy practices in standard format that can be retrieved automatically and interpreted easily by user agents. This is done through a P3P statement, available below. Find out more about P3P at [www.w3.org/P3P/](http://www.w3.org/P3P/ "Link opens in a new window").
